# Brenda Gaceri



### SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

### **Profile**

I am a results-oriented Junior Software Developer with 2 years of experience in using effective programming solutions to address real life problems. I design and develop software across various platforms. I am currentrly seeking technical roles.

## **Education**

### **Bachelor of Science in Computer Science.**

Dedan Kimathi University of Technology 2017 - 2021 Nyeri, Kenya.

# Certifications

#### Bachelor's degree in Computer science.

Dedan Kimathi University of technology, 2021

### **Certificate of training**

Simplon.co, 2021

# Work Experience

#### **Creative Assistant intern**

Kikosi Limited | June 2021, to present

- Researched user requirements of upcoming projects.
- -Segmented users into respective categories.
- Oversaw the design of mockups and prototypes for mobile and web applictions.
- Updated existing interfaces as per user feedback. Recommended best practices for development of user interfaces.
- Resolved discrepancies with existing design and user experience
- Designed and developed world class application User interface in the export field.

### **IT support Atachee**

Kenya Tea Development Agency | Jan 2020 - March 2020

- Gathered hardware inventory asset data and provided assistance with desktop hardware troubleshooting
- Installed and interfaced computer hardware including multimedia, memory and video components and systems.

### **Web Developer**

Simplon.co | Sept 2020 - March 2021

- Collaborated with senior developers in generating prototypes, mockups and minimum viable products
- -Practised basic UI/UX concepts for wide range of users.
- -Designed relational databases and performed basic C.R.U.D functions as well as processing dynamic data.
- -Defined functional requirements for systems and broke down the implementation process into acheivable stages, as part of mastering solutions architecture.

# Skills & Proficiencies

### **Tools and Languages**

- HTML and CSS
- Figma
- MYSOL

- PHP
- Adobe Illustrator
- Git

- Javascript
- Adobe XD

### **Interpersonal communication skills**

I understand the importance of communication within an organization and a team. I have therefore taken the time to practice and hone this skill to work to my advantage in delivering set targets

### System design and development.

The system design and development process is complex and can be a major setback, when one does not fully understand it.

Throughout my studies and career, I have become conversant on the different procedusres that take place in the development of ant system and why these procedures must be put in place.

### Critical thinking and problem solving

These two go hand in hand and throughout my career I have developed a roadmap that has worked in multiple instances. I take time to observe targeted users, analyse their needs then come up with a plan. These three basic steps allow me to focus on the goal, which is always the intended user, to come up with long-term solutions. I am a lover of arts and psychology and often consult them in the design and development process.

### Personal skills

I have come to learn alot about my personality in terms of strengths, weaknesses, opportunities and threats. I beleive in continuously working on each of these elements to develop selfdiscipline which is critical in my career, and also as a leader.

### Referees

### James Mwangi

Senior Software Developer, wiggles technology jamohgich22@gmail.com 0727309037.

### **Gabriel Kimotho**

C.E.O, Kikosi Limited
gabriel.kimotho@kikosi.co.ke
+254721914771

### Rosalia Kaluki

Legal Administrative Assistant, Sanergy rosaliakaluki@gmail.com +254725685545

### Contact

+254 799 238 995
Nairobi, Kenya
michenibrenda81@gmail.com
github.com/Gacheri
linkedin.com/in/brendagaceri/